PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(bouncy Pixar theme)
- In the last exercise you probably noticed
在上一个实例里 你或许会发现
that the simulation lacked the natural bounciness of hair.
模拟的结果似乎不太自然 没弹性
But what makes something look bouncy anyway?
但是怎样才能让它看起来有弹性
To make this model bouncy, we need each strand of hair
要让这个模拟有弹性
to expand and contract slightly
我们必须让这束头发有轻微的扩张和收缩
when forces are applied to them.
当它们受力后
This required a new physical analogy to base our model on,
就需要一个新的物理模型来介入
so we tried springs.
我们想到了弹簧
Springs are great because they can change length
弹簧的好处在于在你拉他们的时候
when you pull on them,
他们能伸缩
and to give the hair a little bit of weight,
还能给头发一些重力
we add a small weight to the end of the spring.
我们在弹簧的末尾加了一点重力
This is known as a mass spring system.
这就是重力弹簧系统
We can actually draw a mathematical model
我们能实际上能建立一个数学模型
to explain what happens when a spring expands and contracts.
来解释弹簧伸缩的时候到底在发生什么
The model we use is based on a law developed by Robert Hooke
其实我们这个模型是基于胡克定律（注释1https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E7%BD%97%E4%BC%AF%E7%89%B9%C2%B7%E8%83%A1%E5%85%8B）
a 17th century physicist.
他是一个17世纪的物理学家（其实他有很多身份）
Hooke noticed that there are two things to consider
胡可发现在考虑弹簧伸缩的受力的时候
when a spring expands and contracts.
有两样东西要注意
One, if we pull on a spring and it expands,
第一：当我们拉伸弹簧的时候
we will increase its length and it will pull back together.
我们会使他延展，而他将产生回力
Two, if the spring contracts, its length will decrease
第二： 当我们压缩弹簧时
and it will push apart.
他会缩短并产生推力
How much a spring pushes and pulls
而这个弹簧的推力与拉力
is known as the spring force.
就是所谓的弹力
Robert Hooke was looking for relationship
胡克就是在寻找
between the spring force
弹簧的弹力变化
in the amount the spring contracts or expands.
何其伸缩长度之间的数学关系
We call this change in length displacement.
我们把这个称作长度置换
Displacement is defined as the current length
置换量是由现有长度
minus the rest length of the spring.
减去弹簧原长的来决定的
When we stretch a spring, the displacement is positive
我们拉伸时 置换是正值
and the resulting spring force is negative.
弹力就是负值
This is known as the pull force.
这也就是拉力
When we compress a spring, the displacement is negative
当我们压缩时 置换是负值
and the resulting spring force is positive.
那弹力就是正值
This is called the push force.
这也就是压力
So Hooke's observation was quite simple,
所以胡克的观察是如此的简单
he noticed that a larger displacement
他发现置换越大
results in a larger force,
力越大
while a smaller displacement results in a smaller force.
反之则越小
That is, he noticed that the displacement
他因此发现置换和力
is proportional to the force.
是成某种比例的
However, every spring is different,
尽管每个弹簧不同
some take a lot of force to displace,
一些需要很大的力来置换
and some are really easy to displace.
而一些则不需要
So Robert Hooke introduced the idea of stiffness
所以胡克引入了弹性系数的概念
to account for how hard it is to displace a given spring.
用这个值来计算多少力用来置换弹力
It is represented with the letter k.
他的数学符号是k.
This led Hooke to his final equation
这就使胡克写出了最终的方程式
which is known as Hooke's Law.
也就是有名的胡克定律
The spring force is proportional
弹力与弹性系数和置换量
to a stiffness times the displacement.
的乘积成线性关系F=-kx
Notice that there is a negative sign there,
注意 这儿有个负号
that's because we want a positive force
因为我们定义置换量为负值的时候
when the displacement is negative,
能得到正数
and a negative force when it's positive.
反之则是负数
If we plug this equation into the computer
如果我们把这个方程应用到计算机里
we get this realistic spring behavior.
我们就会得到真实的弹簧行为
For Brave, we modeled the horse's hair
在brave里 我们就用重力弹簧模型
using a mass spring system
模拟了马的毛发
similar to what we are describing in this tutorial,
和我们在这个教程里差不多
nearly 10,000 simulated hairs in total.
有10000根毛发模拟
In the next exercise you can explore
在下一个练习中 你会看到
a simple mass spring system.
一个简化的重力弹簧系统
You'll be able to adjust the following parameters,
你将可以调节各种参数
mass of the particle, spring stiffness, k,
粒子质量 弹力系数k
and the force of gravity,
还有重力
and we'll ask you some challenge questions
我们会向你做一些提问
to make sure you understand the basics of Hooke's Law. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
来确保你理解了胡克定律 注释2（https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E8%83%A1%E5%85%8B%E5%AE%9A%E5%BE%8B）